<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<component>
  <id>de.linrunner.easytlp</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <name>easyTLP</name>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later AND GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <summary>Optimize laptop battery life with automatic power profile switching</summary>
  <url type="homepage">https://linrunner.de/tlp</url>
  <developer id="de.linrunner">
     <name>Thomas Koch</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
        easyTLP is a feature-rich command-line utility, saving laptop battery power
        without the need to delve deeper into technical details.
    </p>
    <p>
        easyTLP extends TLP with automatic power profile switching based on system workload,
        providing intelligent power optimization for modern laptops. Default settings are
        already optimized for battery life and implement Powertop's recommendations out of
        the box. Moreover easyTLP is highly customizable to fulfil specific user requirements.
    </p>
    <p>
        Settings are organized into the three customizable easyTLP profiles performance (AC),
        balanced (BAT) and power-saver (SAV), allowing to adjust between savings
        and performance independently for battery and AC operation. The Power Saver daemon
        automatically switches between these profiles based on system workload.
    </p>
    <p>

        which lets desktop environments show an easyTLP profile switch.
        Together with easyTLP as the backend for applying the customizable profiles,
        it replaces power-profiles-daemon.
    </p>
    <p>
        In addition easyTLP can enable or disable Bluetooth, NFC, Wi-Fi and WWAN
        devices at boot time, as well as automated switching when a LAN cable is
        connected or removed, or when the laptop is docked or undocked.
    </p>
    <p>
        For ThinkPads and many other laptop brands it provides a unified way
        to configure charge thresholds and recalibrate the battery.
    </p>
  </description>

  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
  </categories>

  <!-- Do we want software centers to automatically launch TLP ? -->
  <!-- <launchable type="service">tlp</launchable> -->
  <provides>
    <!-- Match "Portable" chassis type -->
    <modalias>dmi:*:ct8:*</modalias>
    <!-- Match "Laptop" chassis type -->
    <modalias>dmi:*:ct9:*</modalias>
    <!-- Match "Notebook" chassis type -->
    <modalias>dmi:*:ct10:*</modalias>
    <!-- Match "battery" kernel module -->
    <modalias>acpi:PNP0C0A:*</modalias>
  </provides>
</component>
